so we're just finishing how to think
like a bodh Safa and then we will start
the six uh activities of a buer if gisha
doesn't do too much
fundraising okay all right uh when do I
have to
stop in 15 we go to a
Q&A you tricked me
yesterday no we didn't have any
class
okay yeah we'll do we'll do 15 minutes
and then then me and Stanley are GNA do
a dance okay uh right so no don't get
excited until you see
it okay NJ tomj Chik J yesterday I
taught you Nour and I'll give you not
any money to tell me what's
n yeah yoga yoga okay Nour is the
Tibetan translation of the Sanskrit word
yoga but that there's two translation
periods in Tibet there's the early
period where they translate by meaning
and then there's a later period when
they translate by word so in in the
early early translation period they they
have strange words like Nirvana is
what's that
passing Beyond grief passing Beyond
grief so there were creative
translations in the early time then
later they started to make just dry
drier translation okay so this is one of
the early translations n j means uh
accurate practice D what do you call
Precision strike we can call it
Precision strike this this the Tibetan
word for yoga is precision strike you
know Precision you hit marma you hit
that killing Point precisely immediately
okay it that's the word for yoga it's
very beautiful then he
said you can do all the different kinds
of yoga with one with one action okay by
the way Connie you owe me in
January right that we will continue uh
the YSI
uh 4-year program of the classics of
yoga we are teaching the classical
literature of yoga which is extremely
difficult extremely deep in my
three-year Retreat I translated a lot of
it and I memorized it uh and uh I made
courses and uh we are going through
those courses in
YSI and uh you should get into it it's
it's very beautiful courses and we are
inside of a book called hat yoga prip
which was written 500 years ago it's the
second great book ever written on the
yoga poses what's the first great
book lady nuga okay the yoga sudra
doesn't Teach as there's one line about
as okay so really it's lady nguma which
we translated and we taught it which is
what we learned in the monastery and
then
uh yoga okay how to do haa yoga which is
ha yoga okay so we're going to start the
third chapter in January
okay what's the appropriate idiom I'm
his idiom teacher they promised me $20
per idiom when I teach them English
idioms they didn't pay me yet
I taught them
thousands
good be there or be square it means uh
it's probably the last time I'm going to
teach and it's very deep and very
beautiful uh about yoga and inner Prana
practices and very very deep so if you
don't come you're a
loser okay yeah and it's online and you
know if you want you can come we have a
little bit in iners also if you want to
come to BC much the the restaurants are
much better than
Koto there's only one they only serve
cinnamon roast okay that's my problem
okay uh NJ Chik you can do all your yoga
practice with with one thing so come in
January if you have time uh it's two
weeks I think two week course uh 1 hour
every day something
or my class is an hour we have many
other classes
okay if you
understand you don't have to learn
hundreds of practices okay uh me good
tomj
uh you can just do one okay if you
understand Lo loong means a
special practice which opens your heart
okay it's called heart opening practice
loong and it was invented about a
thousand years ago and people used it
since then and that's what we're and s's
book which is the next book we're going
to publish is a excellent uh it's one of
the greatest present present ations of
lojo and it's going to be available in
two two three months something like
that if the university doesn't give me
too much work
okay uh D okay D people say exchange
self and others okay it's not a great
translation okay
damj is really two practices okay two
practices number one
is to think about that every human being
has equal right to happiness actually
every living being has equal right to
happiness okay uh everybody has equal
right to happiness not one country has
more right not one species has more
right than the other species you know
animals have equal right to this earth
uh H human countries have equal right to
happiness every one has equal right uh
to be happy person and and fish Birds
everybody we cannot ruin the home of the
fish the
ocean and for the humans that's not fair
we all share the same world we all a
living being so everyone should have
equal right to happiness that's called y
okay means equal right so this
meditation it has has two stems number
one you know we all have equal right we
all have equal right animals people
equal right Birds fish
dogs snakes
rattlesnakes equal right okay and human
beings countries each country each race
each religion has equal right to
happiness okay that's called Y and J
means uh do you believe in equal rights
so
deeply that you will give your right
away to another
[Music]
person do you are you really believe in
equal right do you really believe in
equal rights okay your country has more
money or your country has more land or
your country has more oil you know do
you understand equal right enough to
share everything you have to to make
equal to create equal okay if you're
below equal you support this
idea right if your income is very low
you support the rich countries
should help the poor countries right but
if you're in the rich country do you
believe in equal rights enough to share
what you have without government asking
you without Revolution
without suffering people do you have the
strength to put your money where your
mouth is okay oh I support equal right
okay so give half your income
away uh to the people who are who are
having war right now okay and I'm very
proud in
Sedona uh the people that are doing it
they're really doing it okay they are
they are supporting refugees John
Brady's project is all refugees for 35
years
what happens to refugees when there's a
war refugees create it they go to other
country everybody feels sad everybody
donates for six months then they get
tired or there's new refugees then they
have to support the the Gaza Refugee or
something you know there's a new
refugees and then the it's very bad to
be a refugee after one year or two years
because everybody moved to the next
Refugee and the the refugee who's still
poor still hungry still don't have a
place to stay then they get real
problems okay so uh we are supporting
John Brady's project where is John Brady
uh we support them for 35 years we are
we are helping them for 35 years we
don't give them money we have a policy
we don't give them money we give them
skills we teach them computer work and
and they make their own money
uh and they support themselves if I die
if John Dies they will
continue they they have a special skill
I was in New
York me and John Brady did a fundraiser
1997 something like that at
uh what's it called what's that famous
Cosmetics
[Music]
company but it's bubble and bubble but
they were sold to
L estate louder yeah so anyway um we
want to do a fundraiser for John Brady's
project in New York City around 1997 or
something and we know the guy who's Big
Fat Cat in Estee laer the Bumble and
Bumble Division and uh he has a
theater in his company in in Manhattan
which is very expensive and we said can
we borrow the theater for fundraiser and
he said yes so me and John Brady went
there we taught the king of the Dharma
book uh and we we tried to get funds for
the refugee input
project and we had to go the day before
and decorate the place and get the
refreshments ready and we worked very
late and then whenever I go to New York
uh I stay at John's apartment which he
sold he had one of the most expensive
apartments in
Manhattan at at the penthouse of Central
Park this is like a little bit lower
than toua
paradise and it's I don't know what's
the value he was a real
fatat uh executive and he had one of the
most expensive apartments in in New York
by the way later he sold it and gave all
the money to the impr probably okay to
save the books uh
yeah and a few years later someone gave
him a very expensive house in
Sedona I don't know why okay uh
anyway uh so so we went home and we're
really tired and
you know I I I said he said let's go to
bed and and um he had two rooms and he
had a what do you call that kind of
bed Murphy bed the bed comes out of the
wall so I get on that bed he gets on the
couch and I sleep there and I said you
know usually I'd like to have fresh
orange juice in the morning and he said
I don't have any oranges and I said well
can can we get some and he said well
those stores are closed it's midnight
you know but there's a small small fruit
store it's open all night you know so I
went
there and uh I start to look at the
fruit then I there's two Asian ladies in
the store and they start talking to B to
each other and I didn't say anything you
know and I'm listening you know and I'm
I'm picking the oranges and and then I I
went to pay for the oranges you know and
I said uh where are you guys from you
know and they said we're from Tibet and
I said wow uh how are you get a what do
you call Visa how you come to United
States I I I thought you don't have
passport you are you are a refugee and
they said yeah we are we are a refugee
but we live in a special refugee camp in
India and I'm like oh what are you
guys what's it like you know and she
said
well it's very strange because we have a
computer center in our refugee camp and
uh and I said what do you guys do and
they said we take ancient books and we
input them uh uh for this crazy two
American guys you know and I'm like
really and they said yeah and this is
all in English right and uh then I I
didn't say anything and I I said uh
so how did you get a Visa they saidwell
we got we learned programming because we
have a computer center and then we got a
special visa for programmers and we
allowed to come to America we got green
card you know I'm like wow that's
beautiful story you know and then I said
did you meet those two crazy American
guys they're like no we never met them
you know I said okay I didn't say
anything uh but I went outside I started
to cry you know because they said they
said those guys save our life those guys
save our family you know and uh you
know so
uh so I went outside I'm crying he's
crying you know like wow give me five
Chi
CH what do you call in Span in Mexico
choca yeah so we give high five and then
we walk home and I said John get those
guys to come tomorrow we can raise a lot
of
money so he sent uh his assistant to the
food store and uh we told them come
tomorrow Chung we told them where the
Tibetan ladies beautiful outfit then no
one can refuse money you know so they
came all dressed and we had a big
reunion and we're all crying and um it
was beautiful what I'm talking about
that yeah generally people don't help
refugees after after a year or after two
years and there's
no the feeling when you help a refugee
is I'm giving you money and you should
be grateful to me and that's not
lojong okay that's not lojong lojong
says those refugees have a right to half
of your money they have a right to it
you cannot refuse them okay uh they you
must give it to them it's theirs
temporarily you got somehow you got it
somehow you got too much but now
voluntarily you have to share it's very
similar to the introduction of socialism
in China it's very similar it's like
time to share and now everybody has to
share what they have you know and it's
voluntary each person does it uh by
themselves and we called Dum damj means
you have equal right to my money
everybody has equal right everybody
should have equal income equal house
equal car equal income okay and and if
you do it
voluntarily uh you are practicing loo
okay no one tells you you have to do it
there's no Revolution no one shoot you
if you don't do it okay you do it from
your heart it's an inner side inner
Revolution and gisha just mentions it
once and you do
it
right and share what you have okay share
what you have it's it's not yours
really it's somebody else's so you have
to share you don't have a choice don't
give me this $ five for ACI thing come
on you know share really share okay
really
share don't give your ex extra my okay
last story then Stanley gonna talk uh my
my llama he had a
bell uh it's for a
dog it's a dog Bell you know when you
ring the bell the dog will come you know
then he told me when I ring the bell you
come I'm like woo wo you know and then
he will If he if he wants me he will
ring the bell you know and I live
downstairs he lives upstairs I build his
house that's what happened to my hands
and uh so he lives upstairs then he one
day he he he he rings the bell you know
and he says uh he says you know get up
here quick get up here quick you know
and I'm like okay what was this
story no it's something
else
huh
never
mind I'll tell you
later
huh no but why he ring the
bell so he will ring the bell when he
watch me huh you know all the
stories come on
huh that's
it uh so he rang the bell and then I run
up and the Pope the Christian Pope came
to New York City he came to Giant
Stadium this holds 60,000 people and
he's sitting in the middle and there's
and he says he says listen to this this
is really good you know and I'm like
okay and the pope
said at that moment I don't know how my
teacher know what he's going to
say but the pope said don't give give
your
extra
give half of everything don't give 2%
don't give 3% give half of everything
you have give it you know I'm like yeah
he's like yeah you know okay all right
uh that's what this Lo Jong is say okay
and you don't need me to be your police
just do it shut up and do it okay you
don't have to tell anybody I like like
to tell people cuz I'm a bragger but uh
you don't have to tell anybody just do
it okay just do it it's the right thing
to do okay all right